Dr. Saeki will be hurting from this one.
佐伯教授一定覺得很悔恨
Either way,
不管怎麼說
I must thank you for helping me raise my Impact Factor significantly.
我都要感謝你幫我拿到了影響因子
Dr. Takashina used Professor Saeki, completed the Snipe surgery,
高階醫生利用佐伯教授 完成了醫狙手術
only to list Dr. Nishizaki's name at the end of his paper.
不過論文的最後 卻寫上西崎教授的名字
With this, Dr. Nishizaki's Impact Factor had overtaken Dr. Saeki's,
所以西崎教授的影響因子 超過了佐伯教授
virtually guaranteeing his victory in the chairman election.
外科學會的理事長 基本上已經決定是西崎教授
-I guess this makes you top of the class. -Dr. Matsuoka.
-你應該是同期裡面最有成就的了 -松岡
I couldn't pull off what you did.
我就沒辦法像你這樣
Working at a two-bit hospital like Tojo,
去東城大學那種鄉下醫院
sucking up to the local doctors to gather new cases.
為了拿到新的病例 向那邊的醫生卑躬屈膝
Don't get it twisted.
請不要誤會我
I was there to help patients. Nothing more.
我所做的一切都是為了幫助病患而已
Without treatment, there would be no research.
不治療病患，就無法進行研究
I bet they set up a special position for you at Teika, right?
我敢說帝華大學 為你準備了很好的職位，對吧？
It will be sad to part ways,
雖然很不捨
but once Koharu Shimano is discharged,
但一旦島野小春出院
I will also be leaving.
我就會離開
POSTOPERATIVE RESULTS
（術後報告）
Soccer?
足球？
Yeah.
對
She made a promise with Dr. Sera
她跟世良醫生約好了
to play soccer together once she's better.
等她好一點，要一起踢足球
-Can we? -Koharu, the doctors are busy.
-可以嗎？ -小春，醫生都很忙的
Sure.
好啊
We'll play soccer soon.
下次一起踢足球吧
It's a promise.
打勾勾
Yay!
好棒！
-I'll do my best to get better. -Good.
-那我會加油 -嗯
Oh, Koharu!
小春
Is Dr. Takashina quitting Tojo University?
高階醫生會離開東城大學嗎？
After what happened…
畢竟發生了那種事…
But the operation was a success.
不過手術成功了
Koharu looked so happy.
小春看起來很開心
Hmm… I think
我覺得高階醫生
Dr. Takashina is a wonderful doctor from the patient's perspective.
對患者而言是個很好的醫生
Isn't that enough?
那樣不夠嗎？
I don't know much about research or academic papers.
我不是很了解研究或論文那些東西
Whatever people may think,
但是不管別人怎麼想
he was able to bring Koharu back from the brink.
他能夠讓一度病危的小春恢復健康
If that doesn't make him a good doctor…
我覺得這樣就算是好醫生了
Dr. Takashina.
高階醫生
Yes?
什麼事？
Um…
那個…
Why didn't you put Dr. Saeki's name at the end of the paper?
你論文最後寫的 為何不是佐伯教授的名字？
I'll be looking forward to the paper.
我很期待你的論文
Dr. Seigo Saeki… Don't believe him.
不要相信佐伯清剛
To Dr. Saeki, the Snipe…
對佐伯教授來說，醫狙
was nothing more than a tool to win the election.
只不過是理事長選舉的工具而已
I only chose Dr. Nishizaki so that I can continue to save lives
我選擇西崎教授是為了能夠用醫狙
utilizing the Snipe.
拯救更多患者
Remember…
要記住
pretty words alone can't save a single life.
只會說漂亮話，是救不了人的
And so, the battle over the Snipe was brought to an end.
因此，醫狙之爭現在終於畫上休止符
But more foul play was at hand…
只不過背地裡仍然…
This is why you should order to have detailed blood tests done.
所以該讓病患進行詳細的血液檢查
BODY TEMPERATURE
（體溫紀錄）
I see.
這樣啊
Are you being serious?
你是認真的嗎？
Yes. My name was included in the Japan Surgical Journal
對，《日本外科期刊》 其中一篇論文中
as a contributing author.
掛了我的名字
I request the removal of the Snipe paper from the Journal.
我要求撤銷關於醫狙的那篇論文
Dr. Saeki,
佐伯醫生
you realize the removal of the paper
你應該知道，撤銷論文
will also cause significant damage to your own career.
對你自己的職涯也有很負面的影響
I'm well aware.
我很清楚這一點
As a doctor, I cannot allow for an unfinished paper to be made public.
身為醫生，我不能允許 這種不完整的論文公諸於世
But the final case with that seven-year-old girl was very valuable
但最後那個七歲女孩的病例
as the surgery could only succeed thanks to the Snipe.
是多虧了醫狙才能完成的珍貴病例
I believe the success of that operation
我相信那台手術的成功
more than justifies the publication of the paper.
就足以有刊登的意義了
Unfortunately, that patient is still in the hospital,
很遺憾，那位病患仍在醫院
and she is scheduled for advanced blood testing.
而且需要做詳細的血液檢查
-Blood tests? -Yes.
-血液檢查？ -是的
Just in case.
為了保險起見
In that case,
這樣的話
we can make a formal decision after the blood tests come back, correct?
我們等檢查結果出爐 再正式決定，可以嗎？
Very well.
好吧
Mr. Ikenaga.
池永主編
You seem to be quite invested in this paper.
你似乎非常喜歡這篇論文
I believe it is impressive research.
我認為這是非常了不起的研究
Or is it because it's Dr. Nishizaki's paper?
還是因為這是你的密友西崎教授 所發表的論文？
Goodbye. We will talk soon.
那我們下次見
Withdraw the paper?
撤銷論文？
Dr. Saeki came to us to negotiate with the Journal directly.
佐伯直接找《日本外科期刊》談判了
He said that the last Snipe patient needs more blood tests.
他說最後一位醫狙患者 需要進一步做血液檢查
I can't believe it. He's just being a sore loser.
我不敢相信，他只是輸不起而已
We cannot simply ignore what Dr. Saeki proposed.
但我們也不能忽視佐伯說的
Finish the tests and get that patient out of there.
做完檢查然後讓患者出院
Got it?
懂嗎？
Understood.
好的
Well, well…
這樣啊
Dr. Saeki is full of surprises, isn't he?
佐伯醫生真是充滿驚喜，是吧？
You don't plan on giving up your Impact Factor that easily,
但你不會輕易就放棄影響因子
do you?
對吧？
You seem to be enjoying this.
你似乎很樂在其中
A clash of the elite. What's not to enjoy?
一流人士的爭鬥，很刺激，不是嗎？
There's no problem here.
沒有問題啊
She'll be discharged.
她可以出院了
What?
什麼？
According to blood tests,
根據檢查結果
there's an infection in her heart's septum.
她的心臟中膈發生感染
She'll need treatment right away.
需要立刻治療
Wait.
等一下
If it's an infection in the septum,
如果是心臟中膈感染
it wouldn't be unheard of to miss it.
檢查時沒注意到 也不算是奇怪的事吧
-What? -Pretend you didn't catch it.
-什麼？ -假裝你沒注意到
Have her discharged.
先讓她出院
If the public finds out that the Snipe has caused an infection,
如果被發現醫狙引起隔膜感染
it would be a good reason to have the paper withdrawn.
那就會是撤銷論文的好藉口
If she leaves the hospital, the cause will remain unknown.
如果她出院後出什麼事 原因就無關緊要了
-But… -This is an order.
-可是… -這是命令
If you wish to succeed as a researcher, you need to think ahead.
如果你想當個成功的研究者 你就要把眼光放遠一點
Dr. Takashina.
高階
Hello, Dr. Takashina.
高階醫生，辛苦了
-Hello. -Hi.
-辛苦了 -嗯
Koharu will be released soon.
小春很快就能出院了
She's almost ready to play soccer.
她很快就能踢足球了
Yes. That's right.
對，是啊
What is it?
什麼事？
DISCHARGE PERMISSION FORM
（出院許可證）
Turn this in.
把這個交出去
When the kid leaves, so do you.
跟那個孩子一起離開吧
And then, the Snipe will be popularized nationwide.
然後醫狙就會在全國普及
Saving hundreds of lives. But…
拯救成千上萬的性命，只不過…
Aren't you happy about your research?
你對你的研究感到滿意嗎？
Dr. Takashina, what was that about?
高階醫生，那是怎麼一回事？
We'll be able to release Koharu, won't we?
我們能讓小春出院，對吧？
Dr. Takashina…
高階醫生
Dr. Takashina promised to make me all better.
高階醫生答應會治好我的病
Don't worry, Koharu.
小春，別擔心
I'll help you get better.
我會治好你的病
I promise.
我保證
We'll play soccer soon.
下次一起踢足球吧
Yay! I'll do my best to get better!
好棒！那我會加油
Promise.
打勾勾
Pretend you didn't catch it. Have her discharged.
假裝你沒注意到，先讓她出院
I'm such a fool.
我真是個笨蛋
DISCHARGE PERMISSION FORM
（出院許可證）
I…
我…
am a doctor.
是個醫生
What do you want?
到底有什麼事？
It's Koharu Shimano--
島野小春她…
This is about the infection in her heart, I presume?
島野小春有心臟中隔感染的事嗎？
So you knew about it.
您果然早就知道了
I need you to call an emergency conference.
請您立刻召開緊急會議
Aren't things working out well for you?
對你來說，事情都這麼稱心如意啊？
Didn't you say you were finished with Tojo University?
你不是說 你在東城大學的事情都完成了？
How did the infection happen?
那怎麼會發生感染？
During the last operation,
上次的手術
we closed a hole in the septum wall.
我們用醫狙堵住隔膜破損的位置
SEPTUM MITRAL VALVE
（中膈、二尖瓣）
However, the stopper came loose.
但是塞子鬆動了
We can assume the infection started there.
所以可以假設感染是從那裡開始的
I see.
這樣啊
If such dangerous risks are involved,
既然有這麼高的危險性
we'll have to reduce the use of the Snipe at our hospital.
東城大學就必須減少醫狙的使用了
Wait a moment. The Snipe isn't the direct cause.
等一下，醫狙並不是直接原因
You will share the patient's details
患者的詳細狀況
at the conference.
你等到會議時再說吧
So they've named the Snipe operation as the cause.
所以他們說醫狙手術 是造成感染的原因
No, the operation itself was a success.
不，手術本身沒有失敗
No matter the results of the operation,
不管手術結果如何
if we cannot earn the Impact Factor, it's a failure!
得不到影響因子，就是失敗
You have nowhere to return to.
你沒有地方可以回了
I don't want to see your face ever again!
我不想再看到你的臉！
Is it Dr. Takashina?
是高階醫生嗎？
What?
什麼？
Takashi…
高階…
Who the hell is that?
那是哪位？
Mr. Matsuoka.
松岡
I have high expectations for you.
我對你有很高的期待
Yes, sir.
是
And so the Snipe paper
所以醫狙的論文
returned to blank pages.
變成了白紙
Dr. Nishizaki's Impact Factor was reduced,
西崎教授的影響因子被扣掉
putting Dr. Saeki back in the lead.
佐伯教授又回到領先
An infection has been confirmed in Koharu's septum wall.
我們確認患者島野小春 發生心臟中隔感染
If the bacteria spreads, her heart could fail at any moment.
如果細菌擴散 隨時可能造成心臟衰竭
We must operate immediately to remove the infection.
必須立刻動手術移除感染問題
It has been decided that due to her blood being unable to congeal,
因為患者的血液難以凝固
a thoracotomy is extremely dangerous.
我們判斷進行開胸手術會非常危險
Dr. Tokai. What do you think?
渡海，你覺得呢？
We can't operate.
不能開刀
We should try medication.
應該嘗試藥物治療
Let's take a further look at medicinal treatment.
先試試藥物治療，再看情況吧
This concludes the conference.
會議結束
Wait.
等一下
There is one other way we can save her.
還有一個方法能救小春
You're saying that now? What is it?
你現在才說？是什麼？
The Darwin.
達爾文
Darwin?
達爾文？
Darwin. A surgical robot developed in America.
達爾文是美國開發的手術機器人
With a high-spec camera and three operating arms,
配有高畫質攝影機和三隻機械手臂
it can perform extremely precise operations.
可以進行超精密手術
Unlike standard thoracotomy, it needs only small holes to operate,
與一般的開胸手術不同 只需要一個小孔就能進行手術
greatly reducing any bleeding.
大大減少出血量
Darwin could work for Koharu's surgery.
小春的手術可以使用達爾文
Yes, we might be able to use the Darwin.
是啊，用達爾文應該可以
We don't have a Darwin in Tojo.
我們醫院沒有達爾文
Not at Tojo, but there is one at Teika.
東城大學沒有，但帝華大學有
We'll release the patient to Teika and operate there.
讓患者轉到帝華大學 並用達爾文動手術
Are you saying we just give up our patient to Teika?
你是要我們把患者交給帝華大學嗎？
It would be shameful to give her right back!
讓她轉回去帝華，也太丟臉了吧
It's the only way to save her.
這是救她的唯一方法
Even if that's so,
就算如此
will Dr. Nishizaki even accept your suggestion?
西崎教授會接受你的提議嗎？
That's…
這個…
As of today, I'm removing you as attending physician.
從今天起，高階醫生 不再是患者的主治醫生
Koharu Shimano's new doctor will be…
島野小春的新主治醫生是
Dr. Tokai.
渡海醫生
Conference concluded.
會議結束
First at Teika University, and now, at Tojo.
高階醫生先在帝華大學失去地位
Dr. Takashina lost his standing.
現在在東城大學也是
Meanwhile, Dr. Tokai took over as attending physician.
與此同時，新的主治醫生渡海
To care for Koharu,
為了治療小春
he introduced a blood-producing medicine called Nespa.
引進了實驗造血劑“耐血帕”
-Her hemoglobin count is 12. -Give her 20 ml of Nespa.
-血紅素數值是12 -給她20毫升的耐血帕
Right.
好的
Where's Dr. Takashina?
高階醫生呢？
Isn't he coming today?
他今天不來嗎？
Listen, Koharu.
小春，聽我說
Instead of Dr. Takashina, Dr. Tokai will be taking care of you now.
從現在起，這位渡海醫生 會代替高階醫生照顧你
Koharu.
小春
Dr. Takashina is off the team.
高階醫生被踢出去了
Off the team?
踢出去？
-What is… -Don't mind him.
-請問是… -沒什麼
Cut it out, will you?
別再說了，好嗎？
All you need to do is relax, okay?
你現在只要安靜休息就好
Okay…
好
Koharu is still a child.
小春還小
You can't say things like "off the team"…
不能說什麼被踢出去的話
Choose your words better.
不是還有更好的說法嗎？
Dr. Tokai.
渡海醫生
These are Koharu's documents.
這是小春的病歷資料
How long do you plan on continuing medicinal treatment?
你打算讓她做多久的藥物治療？
Who knows?
不知道
Nespa does increase blood count, but it will not cure her completely.
耐血帕確實有助於造血 但不能完全治好她
Wait a second.
等一下
-If her condition gets worse… -If that girl loses her life,
-如果病情繼續惡化… -如果她丟了性命
it will be blamed on the Snipe.
責任就會歸在醫狙上
Dr. Nishizaki will be responsible too as the person who promoted it.
推廣醫狙的西崎教授也連帶有責任
You got orders from Dr. Saeki, didn't you?
這是佐伯教授的命令吧？
So what?
那又怎樣？
You do it then.
不然你來啊
You do it.
你自己治療她
How's the medicinal treatment going?
藥物治療的效果如何？
Who knows? We just started.
誰知道？才剛開始而已
A doctor like you choosing medicinal treatment is quite a surprise.
像你這樣的醫生 竟然會選擇藥物治療，真是意外
I use medicine like any other doctor.
我跟別的醫生一樣會用藥物啊
As long as it helps my clinical trials, I don't mind either way.
也是，只要有實驗結果就好 我不在乎其他的
Koharu. It's almost time for your medicine.
小春，該吃藥了
He said Dr. Takashina is off the team…
他說高階醫生被踢出去了
Don't worry.
沒事的
He'll be back. I know it.
高階醫生一定會回來，我確定
Really?
真的嗎？
He promised, didn't he?
他答應你了，不是嗎？
It'll be okay, so keep doing your best, alright?
不會有事的 所以你要繼續加油，好嗎？
Okay.
好
Let's take your medicine now.
來吃藥吧
Dr. Takashina. The results of Koharu's new tests.
高階醫生，這是小春重新檢查的結果
-Here it is. -Thanks.
-請過目 -好
She's stable, thanks to the medicine.
多虧了藥物治療，她目前狀況穩定
But it can't go on forever.
但如果繼續這樣下去
She won't live much longer.
小春活不了多久吧？
Can't we do something?
我們不能做點什麼嗎？
Koharu has always believed in you, Dr. Takashina.
小春一直相信著你，高階醫生
You're the only one she can depend on.
她能依靠的就只有你了
But you…
可是你卻…
Don't give up so easily.
別這麼輕易放棄
You said we can change the rules.
你說過我們可以改變規則
You have to change the rules.
你必須改變規則
You must carry on with Koharu's operation.
你一定要為小春開刀
Dr. Takashina!
高階醫生！
It's Mr. Makino in 302. He has taken a turn for the worse.
302號房的牧野先生 病情突然惡化了
-Mr. Makino, can you hear me? -Mr. Makino!
-你還好嗎？ -牧野先生
-Deep breaths.
-深呼吸 -牧野先生！
-Thromboembolism of the lungs. -Mr. Makino!
-是肺栓塞
-Who's on duty? -Dr. Sekikawa and Dr. Tokai.
-今天誰值班？ -關川醫生和渡海醫生
I've brought Dr. Tokai.
我帶渡海醫生來了
Dr. Tokai. Take a look.
渡海醫生，請看這個
What a pain in the ass.
真是麻煩
The right and left pulmonary arteries are totally clogged. Furthermore…
左右肺動脈完全堵塞了，再加上
a heart operation in his youth left severe adhesions
他小時候做的心臟手術造成嚴重沾黏
so a thoracotomy is out of the question.
所以不可能從中央開刀
We can't operate.
沒辦法動手術
There is one way.
有個辦法
We open from the left and remove the blood clots.
從左邊開胸，移除左右兩邊的血栓
Both from the left? Is that even possible?
左開胸移除左右兩邊的血栓？ 有可能嗎？
It has never been done, at least not in Japan.
至少在日本還沒有先例
What do you mean?
什麼意思？
I assisted at such a surgery during my time in America.
我在美國時擔任過這種手術的助手
There's no way you could do it. You were just an assistant.
你辦不到，你當時只是助手
Move it.
礙事
No.
不
I'll do it.
我來做
Dr. Tokai, please assist me.
渡海醫生，請你協助我
Sometimes you need to change the rules.
有時候就是需要改變規則
I'll take responsibility.
我會負責
What?
什麼？
Dr. Tokai, please assist me.
渡海先生，請你協助我
Sometimes you need to change the rules.
有時候就是需要改變規則
I'll take responsibility.
我會負責
We'll now begin the removal of blood clots within the pulmonary arteries.
現在開始進行左開胸 移除左右肺動脈裡的血栓
Cooper.
庫柏剪
Dr. Sekikawa. Start the heart-lung machine and lower it to 18 degrees.
關川醫生，啟動人工心肺機 並降到18度
Okay.
好的
-Scalpel. -Here.
-手術刀 -這裡
-Halt circulation. -Right.
-請停止循環 -是
Let's remove the clots. Magill forceps, please.
現在移除血栓，請給我異物夾
-Here. -Miwa, bring the 4-0.
-這裡 -美和，拿4-0號線
Right.
是
Amazing. Such a delicate operation…
太厲害了，這麼精細的技術
This is Dr. Takashina's real skill.
這是高階醫生真正的實力
-Metz. -Right.
-組織剪 -是
Operation complete.
手術完成
Vitals all clear.
生命徵象正常
You look like you're about to die.
你看起來快死了的樣子
Dr. Takashina.
高階醫生
Forgive me for earlier.
剛才很抱歉
I might be out of place asking this,
我這樣問或許有點怪
but how will I take responsibility for this?
但我這樣要怎麼負責呢？
Thanks to you, I've finally realized…
多虧了你，我才終於意識到
I have nothing else to lose.
我沒什麼可以失去的東西了
But…
但是
That's why I have more work to do.
正因此，我才有更多事要做
Tell Koharu that I'll be back soon.
告訴小春，我很快就回來
Okay.
好的
Hey. What are you doing here?
喂，你來這裡幹嘛？
Dr. Nishizaki. Dr. Saeki plans to let Koharu die.
西崎教授，佐伯教授對小春見死不救
If the patient dies,
要是患者過世
you will take responsibility for the Snipe's role in her death.
研究醫狙的您也有連帶責任
Is that a threat?
你在威脅我嗎？
May I use the Darwin?
我能使用達爾文嗎？
What?
什麼？
That's not what I expected to hear.
我沒料到你會說這個
Darwin is Teika's star surgeon.
達爾文是帝華大學的明星手術機器人
I can't allow such a high-risk patient to transfer
我不能讓高風險的患者轉院過來
in case the surgery fails.
冒著手術失敗的風險
I won't be transferring her.
我不會讓她轉院
I wish to borrow Darwin.
我只是想借一下達爾文
-Borrow? -That's right.
-借？ -沒錯
There will be no trouble for Teika.
我不會給帝華大學添麻煩
If there are any problems,
如果出現任何問題
I will take full responsibility as part of Dr. Saeki's department.
提出這個建議的我 會以佐伯外科部門醫生的身分負全責
I'm begging you.
拜託您了
Fine.
好吧
But I don't plan on letting you use it.
但我不打算讓你來動手術
Dr. Matsuoka. The Darwin is your specialty.
松岡，達爾文是你的專業領域
This is a chance for us to gather new cases.
這是收集新病例的好機會
Show Tojo the real strength of Teika University.
讓東城大學看看我們真正的實力
Leave it to me.
交給我吧
I will succeed, Dr. Nishizaki. You have my word.
為了西崎教授，我保證一定會成功
-Dr. Matsuoka as operating surgeon? -Yes. That was the condition.
-松岡要主刀？ -對，那是他們的條件
Acting quite recklessly, don't you think?
不覺得你這樣很魯莽嗎？
I no longer have anything to lose.
我沒什麼好失去的了
Very well.
好吧
Thank you.
謝謝
I'll begin preparations right away.
我立刻去準備
And so, the Darwin came to Tojo University.
因此，達爾文被運到了東城大學
It doesn't even compare to the Snipe.
這跟醫狙的規模差好多
Four arms. That's a robot all right.
四條手臂，確實是機器人
Amazing. It can write on a grain of rice?
太厲害了，可以在米粒上面寫字？
Rice is for eating.
米是用來吃的
What?
什麼？
NAP ROOM
（休息室）
I had heard rumors,
我聽說過這件事
but it can really write on a grain of rice.
沒想到真的可以在米粒上寫字
Like the common folk watching the Black Ships' arrival in Edo, right?
像是劉姥姥進大觀園，對吧？
You bunch of hillbillies.
你們這群鄉巴佬
Hillbillies?
鄉巴佬？
That's what he called us?
他這樣說我們？
He gives me a bad feeling.
他給我的感覺不是很好
How long do they plan on using this medicine?
他們打算繼續用藥到什麼時候？
Dr. Tokai said they would use it until the operating day.
渡海先生說要持續到手術前一天
Really? Until the very end?
真的要到那時候嗎？
It must be doing something.
這有意義嗎？
Trial medicine… something to do with receiving cooperation funding?
這是試驗藥物 所以跟臨床試驗合作費有關吧？
That's part of it, right?
那包含在內吧？
So it's all for money in the end?
所以說到底，這一切還是為了錢嗎？
Mr. Tomizawa.
富澤先生
We've received warm praise
這次的達爾文手術
from the Ministry of Health regarding the Darwin operation.
厚生勞動省給予這麼慷慨的資源
Thank you for your support.
真的非常感謝您的支持
The world of Japanese medicine is outdated.
日本醫療界仍然非常老派
I want to change that.
我想要改變這點
This will require adopting the latest medical technologies
因此需要引進最新的醫療科技
and virtually eliminating the skill gap among surgeons.
並消弭外科醫生之間的技術落差
I agree completely.
我完全同意
Unfortunately, there are a number of people that don't.
但是很可惜，有些人不同意
People with great authority
那些位高權重
who favor the skills of a surgeon.
認為外科醫生的技術才重要的人
Putting it that way,
從這方面來看
the Darwin operation taking place at Tojo
在東城大學進行的達爾文手術
could serve to be quite valuable for us.
對我們來說非常有幫助
Simulations of Koharu's Darwin surgery began.
小春的手術模擬練習開始進行了
-Scissors in the left hand. -Right.
-剪刀換到左邊 -好的
All right. All set.
好，都準備好了
I have no doubt we'll succeed.
我相信手術絕對會成功
Good job.
辛苦了
Dr. Matsuoka.
松岡
This is the first Darwin surgery on a child, right?
你第一次在小孩子身上 用達爾文動手術吧？
Are you sure it will be okay?
你確定沒問題嗎？
Listen.
聽好了
Do you know how many times I've done this?
你知道我用達爾文做過多少手術嗎？
The lot of you at Tojo are a bunch of killjoys.
你們東城的人還真會掃興
Dr. Tokai, here.
渡海醫生，這給你
-The Darwin documents. -I don't need them.
-這是達爾文的資料 -我不需要
I have nothing to gain.
我沒什麼好處
Nothing to benefit from this operation.
沒辦法從這次手術得到什麼
The only thing I hope for
我只希望
is for Koharu's life to be saved.
能夠救小春一命而已
I will do whatever it takes to ensure her safety.
所以我會不惜一切代價 確保她平平安安
People change, huh?
人會變，是吧？
Things change when you lose everything.
失去一切的時候，一切就不一樣了
But you did help me realize something.
你倒是讓我意識到一件事
In university hospitals, doctors with no interest in promotions
在大學附屬醫院裡 對升遷沒興趣的醫生
are the strongest.
是最強的醫生
Doctors like you, Dr. Tokai.
就像你這樣，渡海醫生
Excuse me, Dr. Tokai.
打擾了，渡海醫生
Dr. Tokai…
渡海醫生
What's this…
這是…
The fateful day finally arrived.
命運般的一天終於到來
He's here.
客人來了
Greetings, Dr. Saeki.
佐伯教授，你好
It has been quite a while.
好久不見
Likewise. It's good to see you looking well.
好久不見，西崎教授 很高興看到你的狀態這麼好
Well, ever since the Snipe paper was withdrawn,
沒有的事，醫狙的論文被撤銷之後
I haven't slept much.
我就睡不好
We should be grateful it was withdrawn before something bad happened.
我們應該慶幸 出事之前就撤銷了論文
Your good name was in jeopardy.
不然可是會損害到你的名聲
I hear that today's surgery
我聽說今天的手術
will be crucial to the success of the paper.
關係到那篇論文的成敗
I hope to learn a lot.
我也想好好觀摩
I'm glad you're here.
請多指教
Dr. Nishizaki. Please, this way.
西崎教授，這邊請
Live feed, please.
轉到直播畫面
Please begin.
請開始吧
Okay.
好的
-Here we go. -Tojo's first robotic operation.
-開始了 -東城大學第一場機器人手術
Koharu…
小春
More. More. Stop.
再過來一點，停
The cart is in place.
手術台車就定位
We will now begin septum infection removal surgery with the Darwin.
開始使用達爾文移除中隔感染部位
-Docking. -Right.
-連接 -是
By the way, I heard from a little bird
對了，我聽說
that your team was planning to let the patient die.
你的團隊本來打算 對這位患者見死不救
I'm happy to be able to help.
很高興我們幫得上忙
We're grateful to you for lending us the Darwin.
謝謝你把達爾文借給我們
And enlisting such a skilled doctor.
還派了這麼優秀的醫生過來
Failure seems unlikely, even in a worst-case scenario.
看來就算是最壞的情況 也不可能會失敗
Of course.
那是當然的
Inserting forceps.
插入手術鉗
The holes are so small. Will it work?
開口那麼小，真的可以嗎？
There's hardly any bleeding.
幾乎沒有出血
Maybe the day when we aren't needed anymore will really come.
或許不需要外科醫生的時代要來了
No way. I'm not losing to any robot.
不可能，我才不會輸給機器人
But seeing something like this…
但看到這樣的場面…
All right. It's showtime.
好，好戲要開始了
The tip of the forceps have reached the pericardium.
手術前端已經抵達心膜
-Set the electroscalpel to 25. -Right.
-電燒刀調到25 -好的
Starting the pericardial incision.
開始切開心膜
Thanks to the Darwin,
有了達爾文
even the most difficult of surgeries can be made possible.
再優秀的醫生都難以進行的手術 現在都變得可能
Right atrium open. Give me visuals.
右心房打開，給我畫面
Right.
是
RIGHT ATRIUM BACTERIA
（右心房、感染部位）
Soon reaching the site of infection.
即將抵達感染部位
Now, the hard part.
困難的部分來了
Hard part?
困難？
There's no such thing.
根本沒那種東西
Let's proceed to remove the infection.
繼續移除感染部位
-Such precise work. -That's the Darwin's power.
-好精準 -這就是達爾文的威力
Now it just needs to be removed…
現在只剩下切除了
It appears to be a success.
看來手術要成功了
Time to finish up.
該收尾了
That was a piece of cake.
真是輕而易舉
Removing bacterial site.
準備切除感染部位
Okay.
是
-What the… -What is it?
-搞什麼？ -怎麼了？
What's happening? The forceps won't budge.
發生什麼事？手術鉗無法移動
The forceps won't move?
手術鉗無法移動？
What happened?
怎麼回事？
Blood loss increasing.
出血量增加了
The arms are hitting each other!
機械手臂撞在一起了
This isn't good.
這下糟了
The arms' movement is limited
對於體型小的孩子
when working on the body of a small child.
機械手臂的活動範圍有限
Damn it.
可惡
That's what I was afraid of!
我之前就跟你說了！
Any sudden movements will tear the heart!
如果強行移動會撕裂心臟！
What's happening?
怎麼了？
Can you move the arms?
你會移動機械手臂嗎？
-Wait. -What are you doing, Dr. Matsuoka?
-等一下 -松岡，你在做什麼？
Get ready for conversion.
準備轉換
Koharu…
小春
This is not looking good.
情況看起來很不妙
Someone has to go help.
誰去幫幫忙啊
But no one at Tojo knows how to use it.
但是東城大學沒有人會操作
What's this…
這是…
Dr. Tokai…
渡海醫生
Hey, Miwa!
等一下，美和
We're losing more blood!
出血量越來越多
Dr. Matsuoka. We have to withdraw.
松岡，應該撤掉達爾文
I'm the operating surgeon.
我是主刀醫生
I'm going to remove the infection.
我要繼續移除感染部位
Know your place, Dr. Takashina!
高階，搞清楚你的立場
I never had one to begin with!
我打從一開始就沒有立場可言
-I'll be right back. -Okay.
-我馬上回來 -好
-Dr. Takashina! -Continue the operation!
-高階醫生 -繼續動手術
Dr. Tokai!
渡海醫生
-Move the arms. -We can't. The blood won't stop.
-移動手臂 -不行，也無法成功止血
-Then get transfusion! -She's allergic to blood transfusion!
-那就輸血 -她的體質不能輸血
-We told you! -I can't get a visual!
-我們跟你說過了 -我看不清楚
-Suction! Get the blood out! -Right.
-快點把血抽出來 -是
Dr. Tokai!
渡海醫生
We need your help.
我們需要你的幫忙
Let's go.
走吧
Suction on max! She can't lose any more blood!
抽吸開到最大，她不能再失血下去了
Damn it. We're toast.
可惡，我們完了
Dr. Tokai!
渡海醫生！
Tokai?
渡海？
Dr. Takashina. What do you think you're doing?
高階，你在做什麼？
You didn't take the patient's small body into consideration
你沒有考慮到患者幼小的體型
in adjusting the robotic arms.
所以沒有調整好機械手臂
This is your fault.
這是你的錯
You call yourself a pro with the Darwin?
你還敢自稱是達爾文的專家？
-Write your resignation letter. -What?
-去寫辭呈吧 -什麼？
I'll save you for your severance pay. Ten million yen.
退職金一千萬給我，我就幫你
Don't be a fool! I don't have ten million…
別傻了，什麼一千萬…
Then what?
不然呢？
Let the child die in front of the great Dr. Nishizaki?
你要在偉大的西崎醫生面前 讓這個小孩死掉嗎？
Dr. Matsuoka. Out of the way.
松岡，讓開
What?
什麼？
Get out!
快起來！
Move it.
礙事
-Dr. Takashina. No. 3. -Two cm to the right.
-高階，三號 -向右兩公分
-No. 1. -Three cm to the left.
-一號 -向左三公分
The arms will move now.
手臂可以移動了
-The forceps moved. -We'll take them out.
-手術鉗可以動了 -把手術鉗拿下來
I'll open up her chest.
我替她開胸
You can't do that. She's allergic to transfusion.
不行，小春不能輸血
-So we'll use her own blood. -Her own blood?
-用她自己的血就好了 -她自己的血？
So that's why you were using Nespa, a blood producer.
所以你才會用耐血帕造血劑
You've been collecting her blood.
你一直在收集她的血
-Nekota, how long will she last? -I can give you 30 minutes.
-貓田，她能撐多久？ -30分鐘
Thirty minutes, starting now? Impossible!
現在開始30分鐘之內完成？不可能
Watch me do it.
我做給你看
Tojo University can do it.
東城大學辦得到
-Move the cart. -Right.
-移開手術台車 -好
-Get ready! -Okay.
-準備好 -是！
There's already a hole. Let's connect it.
已經有開口了，現在要連起來
-Scalpel. -Here.
-手術刀 -這裡
-Wipe it. -Okay.
-擦拭 -好
-Electroscalpel.
-電燒刀
-Open it. -Right.
-打開 -是
Think of the next step. We'll open the chest.
想著下一步，我們要開胸吧
-Open it up! -Retractor.
-那就開胸！ -開胸器
-Opening chest. -Remove blood from the heart and lungs.
-開胸 -移除心肺的血
Use suction, you!
你，快點抽吸
-Nekota, muscle hook. -Here.
-貓田，肌肉鉤 -這裡
-Bring it, hurry! -I'll cut it off with the forceps.
-快來 -把阻斷鉗給我
Reclamped. Remove the blood.
重新夾好了，引流吧
-Lend me a hand. Open. -Right.
-借我一隻手，打開 -是
Amazing. He's just as precise as the Darwin.
好厲害，他跟達爾文一樣精細
-No, he's better. -Suction!
-不，他更精確 -抽吸
I knew he was incredible.
我就知道他很厲害
-Dr. Tokai… -Drain all the blood!
-渡海醫生 -快點抽吸
It seems like it was a difficult operation.
看來還是個很困難的手術
To operate on a child's small body,
在這麼小的孩子身上動手術
more precise preparation was necessary.
就必須要有更精確的準備
It was Dr. Matsuoka, right?
他叫松岡，是吧？
He doesn't understand true surgery.
他不懂手術的本質
Taking it out.
切除
-Got it. Suture, 4-0. -Right.
-取出來了，4-0縫合線 -好的
-Suction!
-抽吸 -是
-Metz. -Here.
-組織剪 -這裡
-Suture complete. -Vitals stabilized. No problem.
-縫合完成 -生命徵象穩定，沒有問題
You finish up.
你來收尾
Dr. Tokai.
渡海醫生
Thank you.
謝謝
This is nothing.
只是舉手之勞而已
I am a doctor, after all.
畢竟我是個醫生
The operation was a success.
手術很成功
We learned a great deal, thanks to you.
多虧了你，我們學到了很多
Professor Nishizaki.
西崎教授
I'm glad to hear that.
這是我的榮幸
I'll be leaving now.
那我就先告辭了
Mr. Ikenaga. I will speak with you soon.
池永主編，我們再聯絡
Dr. Nishizaki!
西崎教授！
Dr. Takashina. Amazing follow-up.
高階醫生，後續追蹤做得很好
-Thank you. -I have something to talk with you about.
-謝謝 -我有些事要跟你討論
Please come see me later.
之後再來找我
Yes, sir.
好的
You have nowhere to return to.
你沒有地方可以回了
Wait, please! Dr. Nishizaki, please!
等等，拜託，西崎教授！
After the operation, Koharu made a full recovery
手術之後，小春完全康復
and she was soon to be discharged.
很快就能出院了
Wow! I bet you're ready to play soccer.
哇，看來你可以踢足球了
Yes!
太棒了！
What about Dr. Takashina?
高階醫生呢？
He's getting some special training too.
他也在特訓中
Dr. Takashina, you're awful.
高階醫生，你踢得爛透了
Want me to show you?
要我示範嗎？
-Please. -Okay.
-麻煩你了 -好
It looks like I'll get to stay at Tojo after all.
看來我還要在東城大學待一陣子
What?
什麼？
A nationally produced Darwin at Tojo…
在東城大學研發出國產的達爾文？
That's right. Teika is working alongside Daiichi Industries
沒錯，帝華大學正在和第一重工合作
to produce a Darwin right here in Japan.
研發日本第一台達爾文
I would like to entrust you with the first clinical trial.
我想把第一場臨床試驗手術交給你
But…
可是…
We'll gather the cases and you'll finish the paper before the elections.
我希望你能在理事長選舉前 收集病例並完成論文
We'll be able to gather more Impact Factor.
這樣就能拿到影響因子
Understood.
我知道了
I'm relying on you.
我就靠你了
This project is also being backed
這項計畫的背後
by an acquaintance in the Ministry of Health.
也有我在厚勞省的熟人當後盾
The Ministry of Health?
厚勞省？
That's why this project…
所以這個計畫
has to succeed.
只許成功，不許失敗
It's our last chance.
這是我們最後的機會
There's no running away from where I've found myself.
結果我還是逃不過 必須選擇立場的命運嗎？
-Let's try again. -Let's do it twice.
-再試一次 -再試兩次
Let's go!
來吧
One… Two… Two times!
一、二，兩次！
Excuse me.
打擾了
I have a package for you.
教授，有您的包裹
Thank you.
謝謝
I'll be taking my leave.
那我先告辭了
If both universities join forces, I believe the new Darwin can achieve this.
如果兩間醫院聯手 我認為新的達爾文可以辦到
-Ms. Harue? -This trial is of great significance.
-春江女士？ -這場試驗手術很重要
Can I ask for your cooperation?
我可以請你幫忙嗎？
What a foolish patient.
真是個愚蠢的病患
The black forceps' secret is still being protected.
黑色止血鉗的秘密還沒有曝光
A medical error?
醫療失誤？
What are you saying?
你想說什麼？
There is no room for error in surgery.
手術沒有犯錯的餘地
I also heard that you refused Dr. Saeki's operation.
我也聽說你拒絕了佐伯教授的手術
It's none of your business.
這不關你的事
Dr. Tokai's mother…
渡海醫生的母親
I think it's more about the money.
我想重點是錢
-Twenty-seven victims are on their way. -Not enough blood?
-有27名病患正要送過來 -血袋不夠？
Do what you can to collect more blood.
盡力拿到越多血袋越好
She's running out of blood.
她快失血過多了
That man betrayed my father.
那個人背叛了我父親
Subtitle translation by: Tom Grathwol
字幕翻譯：林婉婷